Frank Harris

Product Leader

202.460.0027 / frank@hirefrank.com / @hirefrank

Profile

Accomplished product leader and executive coach with a background in design, engineering, and data-driven product development.

Built and led high-performing teams at companies like Slack, Betterment, and Etsy. Now coach senior ICs, VPs, and founders at startups, scale-ups, and public companies.

Coaching style combines strategic insight, structured reflection, and 20+ years of real-world product experience. Known for helping leaders gain clarity during periods of transition, growth, and uncertainty.

Experience

hirefrank / Product & Leadership Coach

March 2020 - PRESENT, REMOTE

Independent coaching practice supporting product leaders at startups, scale-ups, and public companies through moments of growth, transition, and strategic ambiguity. (Full-time since September 2024)

Deliver 1:1 and team-based coaching engagements informed by ICF-aligned principles and 20+ years of building product and leading teams.

Partner with senior ICs, VPs, and founders to build soft power, navigate org design, clarify product strategy, and lead with more influence and intention.

Created Frankbot, an Al-powered coaching assistant that supports reflection between sessions.

Write Frank Takeaways, a weekly leadership newsletter focused on product thinking, career growth, and modern metaphors.

Slack / VP of Product, Developer Platform

NOVEMBER 2021 - PRESENT, REMOTE

Slack's (acquired by Salesforce) mission is to make people's working lives simpler, more pleasant, and more productive.

Led and managed PM team responsible for technical architecture, APIs, and Developer/Admin experiences for our Next Generation Platform (an event-driven automation platform).

Directed go-to-market, pricing, packaging, and partner ecosystem strategies. Achieved \$2M pipeline within 90 days of launch by collaborating with Sales, Customer Success, and Marketing on a focused sales enablement pilot.

Acted as Outbound PM, completing 100+ customer calls to present roadmaps, facilitate discussions, and identify pain points.

InVision / VP of Product, Platform & Growth

APRIL 2020 - PRESENT, REMOTE

InVision's mission is to bring design-driven innovation to every organization through visual collaboration.

Led and managed PM team responsible for all product experiences related to enterprise administrators, internal shared services/APIs, and pricing strategy (including revenue growth and cost-to-serve).

Spearheaded fundamental pricing overhaul focused on driving end-to-end adoption (and revenue) within a customer organization. Estimated revenue impact of +12%, launching in early 2022.

Interim Head of Product (April-June 2020) while the CPO was on maternity leave: advised executive team on organization design, product strategy, and oversaw product launches.

Kitchen Rodeo / Chief Wrangler & Co-Founder

MARCH 2020 - DECEMBER 2020, REMOTE

Kitchen Rodeo provides one-of-a-kind interactive online cooking classes led by culinary professionals and experts. Born out of the pandemic, we've raised over \$175,000 for amazing causes and neighborhood restaurants.

Casper / VP of Digital Product

DECEMBER 2018 - MARCH 2020, NEW YORK, NY

Casper is a global sleep company that launched in 2014 with one perfect mattress sold directly to consumers — eliminating commission-driven, inflated prices. The company is one of the fastest growing consumer brands of all time.

Led and managed a 15+ person Digital Product team responsible for all product experiences across our D2C channels (Retail and Ecommerce). Collaborated closely with C-Suite, channel leads, and other executives; reported into President/CCO and COO.

Owned product roadmap and oversaw key launches including a holistic product line refresh and optimizations across our omni-channel experience. Developed org design and processes to drive execution through IPO.

Betterment / VP of Product

MARCH 2016 - SEPTEMBER 2018, NEW YORK, NY

Betterment is the largest, fastest-growing automated investing service, helping people to better manage and grow their wealth through smarter technology.

Led and managed a 20+ person PM, Design, and UX Research team responsible for all product experiences across Betterment's B2C and B2B business lines. Collaborated closely with CEO/co-founder and other executives; reported into COO and engaged with the Board of Directors.

Owned product roadmap and oversaw key launches including a brand refresh, personalized automated guidance, and third party integrations. Developed organization processes to drive execution of customer and

business outcomes, resulting in 4.5x AUM and 2.7x customer growth.

Cover [Acquired by Velocity] / Head of Product \rightarrow EVP PDE

AUGUST 2014 - FEBRUARY 2016, NEW YORK, NY

Defined and executed product roadmap for consumer (Android, iOS), merchant (iOS) apps, and marketing platforms for restaurant mobile payments startup in 3 cities and 300+ restaurants with peak transaction volume of \$1MM per month. Recruited Design and Engineering teams.

Radico / Co-Founder, Product

DECEMBER 2013 - MAY 2014, BROOKLYN, NY

Co-founded; raised a seed round to build SaaS solutions to help grow marketplaces with big data, analytics, and advertising. Recruited Eng talent.

Etsy / Product Manager → Group Product Manager

APRIL 2011 - NOVEMBER 2013, BROOKLYN, NY

Led product development for Etsy's buyer experience and seller advertising platform, managing a team of 10+ product managers and engineers.

Collaborated with the CEO, CFO, and leadership team to translate high-level company goals into product strategy, roadmap, and execution. Oversaw the overhaul and relaunch of Etsy's core buyer-facing page, which drove a 3.5% increase in conversions — the company's largest experimental win.

Built and scaled Etsy's self-service advertising platform, establishing a new, sustainable revenue stream and driving the adoption of a new "relevancy" search ranking system across the site.

Google / User Experience Designer → Sr. User Experience Designer JULY 2006 - APRIL 2011, NEW YORK, NY

Led UX for Google Checkout, News, Maps, and Transit, with a focus on improving search, discovery, and commerce experiences across products.

Created the original transit icon system still used in Google Maps, and designed end-to-end flows for Google Checkout in collaboration with internal teams and external commerce partners.

Championed consistent UX patterns across multiple initiatives while bridging technical and design goals during a high-growth period.

The Washington Post / Interaction Designer & UI Developer AUGUST 2002 - MAY 2006, WASHINGTON, D.C.

Focused on the front-end development and UI design of advertising, circulation and other supporting systems for the newspaper.

Education